Eugene Ng

24 Skylark Ct, New Britain CT 06053 eyn2@cornell.edu | (860) 726 6143

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

I am a technical project manager with 5+ years experience managing fast-paced and requirement-heavy military and commercial contracts. Projects are typically very customer-focused and results-oriented, requiring backbone in dealing with difficult suppliers or customers. In my free time I am a highly curious and active business owner, having won or finalized in multiple design challenges (HeroX, YCombinator) with Presque Labs LLC.

EDUCATION

M. ENG, ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING | UNIVERSITY OF CONNECTICUT 05/2019 - 12/2020 | Storrs, CT

M. ENG, MECHANICAL ENGINEERING | CORNELL UNIVERSITY 01/2016 - 01/2017 | Ithaca NY

B.S., MECHANICAL ENGINEERING | CORNELL UNIVERSITY 08/2012 - 01/2016 | Ithaca NY Minors: English

WORK HISTORY

SENIOR PROJECT ENGINEER | RAYTHEON TECHNOLOGIES CORP

02/2017 - Present | East Hartford CT

Management of over 200 capital equipment projects totaling more than \$100M to meet cost, time, and technical objectives. Focused on best-in-class automated manufacturing of aircraft components and material handling systems.

- Project Ranger Facility (2021) Managed design and development of blades and vanes material
 handling automation for finish and inspection activity in Pratt & Whitney's new, state-of-the-art, 1M sqft facility, in Asheville, NC.
- Automatic Defect Detection System (2021) Definition, development, and testing of new visual
 inspection system capable of automatically detecting and categorizing defects like nicks and dents on
 aircraft components. Helped with algorithm testing, training, and analysis to determine areas of
 continuous improvement.
- Capital Equipment Modernization (2020) Design, implementation, training, and support of modern electronic tools that replaced old processes and workflows. Streamlined and simplified capital equipment process by up to 50% and improved tracking and visibility throughout. Project implementation completed in less than 6 months.
- Linear Friction Welder (2018) Liaison between military and commercial teams in the US and Japan for the install of a large \$10M linear friction welder. Earned trust of and resolved issues between many different supplier and customer teams.

CO-FOUNDER | PRESQUE LABS LLC

07/2015 - Present | Erie PA

HeroX NextGen design challenge winner for airport material transport cart concept, and YCombinator finalist. Mobile app development company behind Context (a text message analytics application), and Revocube (a 3D puzzle game).

PROJECTS & RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

NONLINEAR OPTIMAL CONTROL OF THE COVID-19 PANDEMIC IN CONNECTICUT UNIVERSITY OF CONNECTICUT

Storrs CT | https://github.com/eugeneyng/SEIR_CT

This paper attempts to model the spread of the disease in the state of Connecticut, and formulate a nonlinear closed-loop feedback controller to minimize the number of infected.

WINNER | HEROX NEXTGEN CART DESIGN CHALLENGE, PRESQUE LABS LLC

Hartford CT | https://www.herox.com/nextgen-cart-design-challenge

Design and build of a next generation Airport Material Transport Cart, to track and transport secured goods from a central receiving center to retail stores, storage areas, and operation facilities within an airport. Created and fabricated entirety of electronic circuit board and developed Python code for user interface and sensors.

ARACHNABOT: SPIDER-INSPIRED ROBOT | COLLECTIVE EMBODIED INTELLIGENCE LAB Ithaca NY

Design, fabrication, modeling, and analysis of a to-scale jumping robot with spider-inspired joints. Led mechanical and pneumatic design and responsible for micro-fabrication using advanced 3D printing technologies

CORNELL CONCRETE CANOE | CORNELL UNIVERSITY

Ithaca NY | https://cornellconcretecanoe.com

Project management of 30-person team for the ASCE Concrete Canoe Competition, including design and testing of different hulls, molds, and concrete mixes. 3rd place finish (2016).

SKILLS

ANSYS, C#, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, KiCad, LaTeX, MATLAB, Microsoft Access, Python, SolidWorks, Visual Basic for Applications (VBA), Structured Query Language (SQL), Wordpress